It's like a vibe coded thing. They're
like and AI was like and now you here's
the slashcookies edit point. It was like
I didn't ask for that. Don't don't write
that.
>> Best part of backing when you can just
you know critical thing right
dude.
[Music]
One of the cool things about going to
these live hacking events is the ability
to look at what you found and what other
people have found and understand where
the holes are in your methodology,
right? By comparing notes. Um, and
thanks to Adobe sponsoring this episode
today, we have an opportunity very
similar to that for you guys. Okay, so
here's how this is going to work. Adobe
has agreed to give you guys a 10%
onetime bonus on your first valid report
to any of the following products. Listen
closely. Adobe Behance, Adobe Portfolio,
Adobe Fonts, Acrobat Web. Okay, those
four. And to get that, you have to use
the code CTBP0907.
Okay, the the description will have that
information. Also, this is valid through
September 7th, right? So, keep that in
mind. Then, what we're going to do on
top of that is we're going to do a
hackalong in the CTB Discord for
everybody, okay? And we're going to
start looking at these targets. And so
what'll happen then is you guys will
take a look at it. You'll see what you
can find. Then we'll do the hackalong
and everybody will be hacking on them,
finding vulnerabilities. I'll be hacking
on them, finding vulnerabilities. And
then we can compare notes and see where
we missed the sketchy pieces of uh
information or the leads or the
vulnerabilities themselves. Okay, so
really good opportunity. This is the
kind of stuff that we have at live
hacking events and Adobe is bringing
this to you guys. So definitely check
out those targets. They're in the
description along with the code. Also,
the Adobe team wants me to let you know
that they're going to be at Besides Las
Vegas sponsoring August 4th, August 5th.
Come check it out. Go to their booth,
have a chat with them. They'll also be
at Defcon in the Bug Downey Village. Um,
so if you see anybody with like Adobe
swag or whatever, don't hesitate to come
up and say hi. All right, that's it.
Thank you, Adobe. Back to the show.
Sup, hackers. I am pulling myself away
from a live hacking event right now to
give you the tw segment for this week.
Uh the this weekend bug bounty segment
is where we cover quick hits on news
that you need to know about um even if
we're doing like an interview or
something like that. Uh so here here's
what we got for this week. First up is
the platform panel on triage at
Bugmounting Village Defvcon. This is a
super stacked lineup guys. Listen to
this. Michelle Lopez from Hacker 1. Our
boy Michael Skelton aka Kodingo uh from
Bug Crowd. Our boy Ini from Integrity.
Eddie Rios from Synak. Anthony Silva
from Yes, We Hack and moderated by none
other than CTB's own JRock. Okay. Who's
been on the pod several times, amazing
hacker and was once on the um on the
triage side as well. So, um this is
going to be a great panel. Definitely
check it out. Uh Saturday, August 9th, 3
p.m. at Defcon. All right. Uh next up is
Yes We Hack is making their debut in
Vegas. They wanted us to let you know
that they're going to be around. Uh
swing by booth 2367. meet the team.
They've got a really awesome group of
people there. Um I know specifically
Alex Broomman has done a lot in the
hacking community. Um lots of really
talented people. Um and the SB hack
team. They've been pushing out amazing
content. Um so if you're hitting uh
Black Hat, definitely uh stop by and
check check them out. Um up next very uh
appropriately is uh a new dojo from Yes
We Hack. Okay. And if you haven't
checked out Yes We Hack dojo, these
things are freaking awesome. Okay. Um,
this one in particular here as a little
bit of like, uh, you know, time time
prediction tokens and, uh, some DC
realization going on. So, uh, definitely
going to be an awesome one to check out.
Last but not least, we have GMS Gadget.
Okay. And if you guys haven't heard of
this, this is a new project by, uh,
Kevin Mizu, who's on our research lab
team here. Um, he released this, uh, and
I just, Dude, I love Kevin's style. like
right right at the top here he's like
this project is inspired by the work of
and then lists a bunch of people from a
2017 a black hat talk and that's like at
the very top of his page so humble so
giving respect to the original
researchers um and then he put together
all of these gadgets um so let let me
let me explain what it is I got a little
over excited here GMS gadget is give me
a script gadget is what it stands for
it's a collection of JavaScript gadgets
that can be used to bypass XSS
mitigations uh such such as con uh
content security policy and HTML
sanitizers like DOM purify. So think
about the episode with um with uh Johan
Carlson, right? You know how much we
talked about uh gadgets, right? Um this
is a place where you can find a lot of
these gadgets depending on what kind of
uh you know what JS libraries you have
installed in your environment. So
definitely a good project to check it
out. We'll link it in the description.
Um, if any of you really are working in
a very tight CSP environment, this is
your new best friend. All right, that's
it for today. Let's go back to the show.
Where's your Reszo? Where's your hops,
man?
>> I'm already sitting down like all
>> right, whatever, dog. Whatever. All
right, here we are. We're rolling.
Harley arm flaps.
>> Okay, there you go. Nice. Thanks for
that. Now, I'm gonna have to redo the
intro. Yeah, sure. Um, all right. We're
rolling. Harley Ari, welcome to the
podcast, guys.
>> Thanks so much for having us.
>> Yeah, thanks for having us. Happy to be
here.
>> Um, so here's what we do. You know, when
we come on the Critical Thinking
podcast, we drop some bugs. So, um,
Harley, before we even before we you
need to earn the right to get an
introduction here on the pod. So, um,
dazzle us with a little bit of a bug
story. Um, and then we'll move into
introduction.
>> Yeah. So, I mean, honestly, none of my
bugs are really all that impressive. Um,
but you know, Joseph, I think you had a
buddy on the pod. His name was Aaron a
couple months ago. It was a great
episode if you know go check that one
out if you haven't seen it. Um but when
I was watching that episode, he was
talking about hacking applications and
that was a topic that I had spent a lot
of time doing. Um and it turned out like
the blog that kind of inspired my
research into that area was actually
his.
>> Um and so I thought it was super
interesting. So when I was pin testing
for a company, I was I came across this
like support portal and when just
interacting with it, I would see a bunch
of post requests to this aura endpoint
that I never really saw before, right?
I'm sure you guys all have probably seen
this.
>> Oh yeah.
>> And so when I came across that blog, I
just like I like was googling like what
is this aura thing? I came across that
um and just following it like step by
step, you know, was a gold mine and was
able to to pop, you know, some access to
things that were pretty critical like
getting into support portal tickets,
things like that, seeing attachments. It
was crazy. And so that kind of like led
me down this rabbit hole of like
wanting to do this at scale for Bug
Bounty because this was before I'd ever
done anything with Bug Bounty before.
And so um I if if you've ever kind of
popped that bug, it's very tedious. Like
you have to start by like enumerating
all the custom objects. You take all
those objects and you have to like query
each one by one and then you have to
validate like okay here's this ID use
that ID to download this file and then
you have to then open the files and
check the responses and some of it might
be like intentionally public and
notative and so you kind of have to like
manually validate that
>> and so it was the perfect thing to try
to like write a tool for to do if you're
trying to do it at scale
>> but I've never been a great like
programmer I've never been able to write
code very well Um, and so it wasn't
until I started working at Hacker 1
actually where I uh I partnered with a
buddy of mine and we kind of like
created like this V1 of this tool and
then we started just throwing against
like Project Discovery's chaos list and
blocking it out everywhere.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, and then anyway, that just kind of
like led to probably my first floor like
flurry of bugs um that I ever got in Bug
Bounty. And it all kind of like started
from Aaron's, you know, blog post. So, I
just wanted to call out that like that
dude has done some really cool stuff and
so having him on the pub is really cool
to see.
>> Yeah, he's still finding stuff. He's
speaking for App Omni at Black Hat I
think this year um like on one of the
main stages I'm pretty sure about um
even more findings and
>> that's amazing.
>> Wow, dude. Yeah, I I I also really like
the the um the thing you said there, the
flurry of bugs. I like I was thinking
like swarm flurry. Like I like the the
visual aspect of that. Um, and surely
there are those times, you know, when
we're hunting where, you know, you find
individual bugs or whatever and you try
to extrapolate them as much as you can,
but it is really cool when you find a
pattern and then you spray it and you
just get a ton of bugs flowing in. Like
that was one of when I did this research
on Graphana with the unauthenticated
SSRF back in um 2020. That was like one
of the craziest times of my bug bounty
career because it was just multiple
crits every day for like weeks and
coming off of that research. Um,
flurries of bugs, man, they they feel
great.
>> Yeah, it's really cool when you have
like a technique or you even if you find
someone else's technique um and then you
just kind of like learn how to
capitalize on it and it can just kind of
keep paying you dividends throughout
throughout your journey. Um, you know,
now nowadays I've been able to turn that
into like a V2, you know, script with
Vive coding and just actually built this
thing out that like, you know, really
helps with automation and and, you know,
so it's it's really cool. Like I'm a lot
more dangerous now with with AI being
where it is because now when I have
these type of ideas, I can actually turn
them into tools and scripts where I
couldn't do that before. And so
>> yeah, dude, you've been you've been
putting out a lot and and I I've been I
kind of want to pick your brain on this.
uh you know cuz I know your job at
Hacker 1 is not a walk in the park and
and you're also doing a bunch of stuff
here um with Bug Bonnie Village with
disclosed with all sorts of stuff. Um so
we'll we'll get to all that but you've
earned your introduction. All right guys
this is this is Harley infinite login um
and and we've got Ari here as well. Uh
these guys are both the squad at the
Hacker One live hacking events. you
know, when you if you ever make it to an
H1 live hacking event, they um they are
the faces that you see and you uh you
know, hang out with. Um so that's how I
know these guys. But um they're also
running Bug Downey Village at Defcon,
which is something we kind of wanted to
uh double click into for this episode is
kind of talk about what we can expect
this year. Um and and man, it went
amazing last year. Last year was like a
knockout success. Um so I'm really I'm
really looking forward to um to this
year. So, I mean, I'm I'm looking at the
dock here, guys. Uh, you know, where do
we want to start? Do we want to talk a
little bit about what you guys have
planned for Pugani Village? Um, at
Defcon. Um,
>> let's give them both a quick intro
first. And, and just to clarify to
everyone, Bugani Village is totally
independent of like stuff that Hacker 1
has going on. You know, Hacker 1 of
course supports it, encourages it, and I
think is also a sponsor, but these guys
are doing this independently of that.
So, definitely give them a lot of
support and praise for that. tell them
thanks if you're under them at Bug
Bounty Village or even on social media
or if you're tuning in um online or
watching the recordings later because
it's um it's a big workload. It's a big
lift for them to do that. Um and it's
really cool they do that for the
community.
>> Yeah. See, I thought we were giving them
an intro, right? So, do do you want to
like
>> I mean I mean on the docket we have
information about them that you didn't
say like lots of it here. So, that's
really what I'm what I'm pointing out.
>> Okay. Fine, dude. Fine. All right. Let
me say let me say uh Justin I'm
partially offended that you didn't ask
me for a bug you know like I know I'm a
shitty hacker but
>> you know
>> Ari dude we added you to this call like
five minutes before this episode.
>> I know but that's the thing you know
like whatever don't worry I'll give
>> Hey if you do do you have a bug you want
to talk about a bug?
>> I do have I do have listen dude like if
I was coming on a pod and somebody like
on the fly was like hey Justin tell me
about a bug you had I would be like uh
you know I didn't really think about a
bug in advance. I wasn't prepared. But
that's the thing, you know, I'm always
prepared, you know. That's that's a cool
thing. No, I'm just
>> What you got, man?
>> Uh, no. Again, I I I do agree with
Holly. Like definitely my bugs are not
even close to any of the things I see in
like hacking events. Like like I feel
the shittiest hacker when I see a show
and tell. It's like, dude, like you
think you're a hack and you see those
things, it's like
>> I'm so crappy. But uh I I do like you
know a lot of the you know idors and
authentication issues and and APIs and I
feel like the APIs especially are like
non you know not the main focus of a lot
of people you know a lot of people go
straight into web apps and and you know
the easy stuff or like the
>> the you know uh they they look for the
ids and the crosscripting all the things
especially if you're not like super
super technical and I think sometimes if
if you find the proper endpoints of you
know uh APIs and and you find the
swaggers uh the endpoints um that that's
what I like to do uh and then I start
like one by one like all the endpoints
and see you know what they do and and
you know the authentication should they
be you know using credentials should do
you need a token for it do you need a
permission or something and
>> I am very good at doing the shitty you
know manual work that nobody wants to do
you know maybe you're probably going to
write an automation
is going to buy code [__] I'm I'm
literally like one by on like one tab in
the burp or Kaido, whatever you use, you
just like creating one tab at a time and
and like trying the the endpoint. And I
have found so many bugs that were super
cool and and some of the things that you
find there blows your mind. I I remember
this one. And I was sitting a web app
and and like again got the swagger and
start again endpoint and I find this
endpoint which is this kind of be real
you know like there's like slashcookies
or something and I'm like
why why do you need this and I start
accessing it and suddenly it brings me
all the cookies of the people logged in
at the time and at the dude I don't even
know what what that was there it was in
production
>> and it was it was like this kind going
to be real, you know, like why is this
being used? Like is someone spying on
us? You know, like all those things and
and you will basically hit this end
point and you get all the cookies and
basically it's a session, you know, take
over for any account that you know it
will be online at the time. So you will
try it like multiple times and you'll
get like different cookies for different
usernames. So again, nothing super
crazy. It's like literally like a
repeater tab, super easy to exploit. But
the severity of that, the impact of that
and and the things that some people miss
because this was not like a you know a
new program. It was there and yeah so so
I guess the takeaway is like you know I
I love swagger endpoints. I feel like
there we need better list to reinforce
some of those end points sometimes you
know those are not extremely
>> you know visible there. Um,
>> yeah, the the Kiterunner stuff by the
Asset Note team really helps with all
that too, right? Like the the brute
force software specifically designed for
the APIs. Um, and and I think that is a
great shout though because like the a
lot of people will focus on like the the
main app and the APIs that power those
main app, but there's also a client-f
facing, you know, API sometimes that has
weird stuff attached to it uh and and
doesn't have the same security
boundaries as the API that powers the
main app. I do I do think that yeah,
I've had a lot of success fuzzing I
think on um organically found paths. So,
a lot of times you'll be hacking an app
and there'll be some API calls like
you're talking about Justin and um
they're like six or seven paths deep and
I think very few people are then like
taking that and then truncating it and
like fuzzing at each level and a lot of
times at one of the at like the third
level deep you'll find a swagger file or
whatever else
>> and the the cookie disclosure reminds me
of like um Django debug mode enabled or
whatever where you can get that exact
same thing. It's like why do devs really
need cookies of active users? They they
never need that. So why is that in any
kind of uh like why are there ever dev
points that do that?
>> It's like a it's like a vibe coded
thing. They're like and and AI was like
and now you here's the slashcookies edit
point like I didn't ask for that. Don't
don't write that.
>> Um oh my gosh, man. That's great. Well,
Ari, dude, I'm impressed, man. Nice
work.
>> You're impressed with that. That is
shitty. I mean, there's not even a clear
clever bug, but you know, it's
>> it's good, man. It's good. You know, I
guess I know that I know that I've run
into you guys mostly in your your
community management um roles at H1, but
it's great to sit down and talk some
talk some technical bugs with you guys.
Um so, um yeah, I guess let's go since
since we're doing more thorough thorough
intros here, Harley, we'll do you first
and then we'll move to Ari. Can you give
us a little bit of a history of how you
ended up in the bug bounty world? Like
where where did your where did your
hacking journey start and and why did
you end up where you're at now? Yeah,
man. So, I mean, I I started hacking at
like 14. Um, you know, back back then I
was playing this game online. I I've
heard so many stories start out this
way, but I was I was playing this game
online. Um, and some dude tried to fish
me.
>> And so, this is like 2010, like fishing
wasn't quite as prevalent as it is
today, right? Um, but he's like, "Hey,
add me in Skype and we're going to do
this thing." And long story short, he
ends up dropping a fishing link. And
I've never seen this before. And but I
noticed like a few things were wrong.
Like I said liketk in the domain. The
like copyright year in the footer was
like a year out of date. There was like
a broken image on the page. So like I
could tell like hey this wasn't legit.
But um I also was like you can't just
clone a website, right? So like I just
thought it was the coolest thing ever.
And so I started begging the dude. I'm
like bro you got to teach me how to do
this. You got to teach me. And he just
>> Yeah. No, but also please. That's great.
So he just he just blocked me, you know,
and I never I never hear from him again.
Um, so I spend like the next two weeks
coming home from school just like
googling like how to make fishing
websites. And so I'm starting to play
with all this stuff, playing around with
like, you know, Dark Comet and remote
administration Trojans and things like
that. And um, I had no idea what the
hell I was doing. It was very much a
script kitty. Um, but that's what kind
of led me down this path, right? And um
when I found out that there was a school
nearby that had a cyber security
program, I was like I was like I think
this is what I want to do. So while I
was in high school, I just hit them up
and I'm like hey can I like sit in on
this ethical hacking class and they're
like okay. And so I was like able to get
exposure and it kind of solidified like
yeah this is what I want. Um so I
started down that path got an associates
degree in cyber security and then after
that started working kind of like
traditional help desk admin type stuff
doing all like firewall config you know
management of active directory things
like that. So, I did that for about four
years at an MSP um before I had an
opportunity to finally go to Defcon.
Actually, back in like 2019 was my first
year going to Defcon.
>> Um and I kind of just scraped up enough
money to like couch surf and and make it
there. Um, but once I was there and like
in the environment of of all the other
hackers, it kind of just I don't know
like something something clicked for me
where I always wanted to be a hacker,
but I got stuck doing this like CIS
admin stuff. And at some point I started
thinking like, oh, hacking is only for
like smart people and I'm not I'm not
able to do that, you know? Um, but I
don't know like I just realized like if
I'm going to make it happen, like I'm
going to have to be the one to make it
happen. And I started going down like
the OCP journey, just learning a lot,
consuming as much content as I could
about this stuff, finding local
communities. There's like a local
security meet up here in Portland called
Rainseac. That group is awesome and
helped me a lot. And I don't know, just
really trying to uh brute force my way
into becoming a pin tester. And I
finally made that transition in 2020.
Um, at that point I just as I was
learning things I would write about
them, you know, like I'd watch like an
IPSC video, um, learn a new technique or
two and be like, "Okay, like instead of
saving it as notes on my computer, I
just like like published it on a blog."
>> And honestly, it was because
>> I kept switching computers and I didn't
want to like
>> I just wanted to always have my notes
with me. Um, but other people started
besting me and they were like, "Hey,
this is really helpful. It's really
valuable." like it was somehow getting a
lot of traction as a blog. Um, and then
that kind of like transitioned into
well, hey, if people like this content,
let me make YouTube videos about it. So,
I did a YouTube thing for a little bit.
I got like 10,000 subscribers on YouTube
that I'm just not I'm just not active
anymore, but I used to upload a lot. Um,
>> and that's when I created like the
infinite login brand and everything.
>> Yeah.
>> So, I did that and then, you know, was
pin testing. I became a security
operations manager for a bit. So doing a
little bit of like blue team work. I
also managed like another pin tester and
then eventually like I just you know
Hacker 1 reached out and they're like
hey you want to come do community
management manage our pinest community.
>> I was like sure let's do it. That's when
I met Ariel and started working at
Hacker 1. Um, I've been there now for
the last three years and being in that
environment, meeting people like you,
like it's really kind of like fired me
up to do, you know, Bug Bounty and give
that a shot and transition. And that,
I'm not going to lie, the transition
from pin test mindset to bug bounty
mindset is a whole different whole
different piece.
>> Um, but yeah, I've been able to kind of
overcome a lot of that and started
having success in Bug Bunny this past
year actually. And I'm working on an
ebook right now to talk about my Bug
Bunny kind of like journey and and how I
really found that success and like what
worked differently for me. And so that's
that'll be coming soon.
>> Dude, what the heck? What how are you
finding time to do all of this stuff?
You're working on the ebook. This is
Okay. Okay. So anyway, we'll we'll we'll
come back to that.
>> Well, first
>> Yeah. Okay. Go.
>> Yeah. So, the first thing I want to say
is I'm gonna introduce Ari in just a
second. Let him introduce himself. But I
just want to mention that I feel like
this arc of like finding like being a
hacker something awesome to do and then
like kind of radically pursuing getting
to Defcon like like getting a security
job then getting to Defcon and then like
you know basically doing cool stuff and
writing about it and then you know other
people encouraging you to do that and
then following like existing hacking
content creators and then eventually
creating content yourself feels like
just such a journey that so many people
have been on. it just really works,
right? And I do think that like what you
said like I I realized that like if I'm
going to do this, I have to do it. I
think that kind of like radical
self-belief, even if it comes with a lot
of imposter syndrome, was like super
true of my story and has been true of so
many other people's stories. So anyways,
I just wanted to highlight that like if
you are up and coming or
or if you are like um kind of unsure
about of yourself, I just feel like the
the um the patent or like the the
blueprint is laid out there, right? Like
just get so stoked to be at Defcon with
a bunch of other awesome hackers. Hold
that in your eye as like your goal or
whatever. And then use current existing
free content out there from like content
creators or you know this podcast or
whatever else to then like just like
learn and fuel your learning, but make
sure that you're sharing it because then
that encouragement that comes from
people that are like, "Oh, you found
that or oh this idea or this lead or
whatever will then like help you kind of
create complete the arc, right, and keep
going." So
>> super cool. Ari, do you want to give us
uh your intro? what got you into hacking
originally and then how did you end up
where you are now?
>> Yeah, definitely. So, I won't make it
super long and boring um with my pentest
life, but definitely I started the whole
hacking situation with when I was hired
at Deote, one of the big four you know
consulties. So, um I didn't hack much
before besides you know cracking some
video games or like you know and by
cracking I mean copy pasting a file into
a folder. don't get
>> right
>> that type of cracking and or you know
like hacking my sister's laptop like
whatever you know like that kind of
thing but I was never thinking about it
as a as a career right but I was in the
university doing like you know
engineering and things like that
>> I was not having fun uh eventually I I
yeah I got hired at the Lloyd I I
started doing pentest and I definitely
learned everything I know from from
there um because you know that got me a
path you know I was shadowing someone
they would teach me. They were super uh
you know friendly. They were a great
team. They're still my friends today.
And that got me to like pentest over
pentest and pentest and you know
consultancies right? It's like
>> you are the expert
>> on everything. Uh and you learn dude
like you I I used to travel to different
countries and and you know like doing
pentest and I wasn't expert but I was
like
>> I was getting shitty payments and and
you know but I was investing in my
career like I'm learning. I like it. I'm
traveling. I'm I don't care if I you
know I kind of have to pay my lunch with
a credit card. That was that was kind of
my my thinking.
>> Um and that's real by the way. It's it's
you know it used to happen but I was
like okay I'm investing in my in my my
career so I'm I'm okay with it. And and
eventually you know I moved to a
different company. Um and at the time I
I was trying to go to Defcon like Defcon
to me was like a passion was like how do
I go there? How do I make my company to
pay for my trip? because I you know I
don't have the money to pay the whole
thing you know uh it's super expensive
so I was like okay this training budget
and you know I was doing my best to you
know get my training in defcon you know
specifically eventually I went there um
luckily multiple times and I remember
2017 uh defcon I was there with these
you know the company paid for my trip
and I have this friend Neman he's
currently doing backing as well he used
to work with me at the loy as well we're
pentesters there and he was doing back
money back hunting at the at the side at
that time back money hunting is not what
it is today you know
>> it was a struggle dude like I I will see
his you know all the payments it was
like one critical $50 you know like it
was really growing up it was trying to
be what what use you know it is today um
I'm I'm talking you know before 2017 but
>> then by 2017 there were like like
hacking events and like things were
getting together and Neiman Seg was you
know invited to Las Vegas live hack
event 702 which is you know big big
thing and at this time we you know
hagwan used to do it in this rooftop
with a pool and like all hackers were
super you know like I don't know like
you will go in there it's a rooftop and
hackers are hacking and like people are
having drinks and
>> it was pretty so sick dude I I was like
I don't know what this is but I want to
be in I want to be part of this however
ever. Like I don't give a crap, you
know, like if I need to do back money, I
will do it. If I need to work here, I
will do it. I don't care. Um, and other
people just, you know, they're just
steal swag and, you know, like I did it
myself as well, you know, but getting
free drinks, it's Vegas, everyone is
partying. I was like with a different
mindset, dude. I was like, I'm
networking the hell out of this, you
know. I'm talking to every single person
who has like a hack one t-shirt or
something. I was talking to everyone,
meeting people and I made friends there
like you know I I met some some cool
guys uh the VP of engineering at the
time hack one Alec he was great and Alex
and and yeah we started talking and like
again networking and stuff like that and
I'm like dude I am a hacker myself I
have a huge community in Argentina I
want you to come to Argentina for life
you know and
>> I want you to come to Wenocidis you know
it's like I want this in Monocitis in my
country and I'm very passionate you can
hell. So, I'm helping you. I mean, like,
I don't care. I will help you to do it.
And they were like, "Okay, we'll see."
And I was I was like, "Okay, it's never
going to happen." Um, and eventually
2018 September, I received an email and
it's like, "Hey, you know what? We are
actually going to Monocitis."
>> And I'm like, "Oh my gosh, what the
[__] That's sick.
>> Yes, that's like so cool." And I'm like,
"Call me in, you know, like I I can help
with whatever." And they were like,
"Yeah, can you help us with, you know, a
venue for like a happy hour or like a
venue for this or like
>> uh we also need your recommendation for
local hackers because, you know, we
don't know Buenosides and like we don't
speak Spanish. So, you know, we need
translation and and I was like, I will
help you. I don't care. I I of course I
didn't get paid." It was like all
passion uh all passion project for me
and eventually that happened. So we did
the you know that event H1 5411 in
Buonitis and yeah I invited like I don't
know 20 hackers or 30 hackers you know
uh from the local community and and I
think they kind of got mind blown
because a lot of those hackers
got their first bounty in that event
including myself including Delhi Seed
which you know is is one of the hackers
I was collaborating a lot that
>> who who was the Target
>> uh the Paranoids. Um at the time, you
know, they're not called the Paranoids
anymore, but the Paranoids were at
Target. And yeah, at that time, well,
Stoke was here, France Rosen was here,
Ini was here, um Neils, um I don't know,
a lot of names.
>> What a lineup. What a lineup. And And
but also at the same time, it probably
wasn't like a huge budget or something
because we also invited these 20 30
people from the local community, you
know. I I I got a bunch from Bonosites
specifically, but also some from Urai or
Chile or Brazil. So, and yeah, I I made
my first bounty there, like paid bounty.
I got like 20 or 30 duplicates before
that, which was like very frustrating,
>> so sad. Um
>> and and and yeah, and and I got like a I
don't know, collaborating with Delis, it
was like a
>> $12,000 bounty or something, and we got
six games. Dude,
>> for us was like
>> that's massive. Yeah,
>> imagine from coming from dupes and dupes
and zero bounty to actually getting, you
know, 6k total for the event or
something. Again, for the event
>> to, you know, see what people are making
today for the event is nothing. 6K is
nothing, but for someone new
>> coming from dupes,
>> first block three triing hacking event
and getting like, you know, two critical
or something, it was 12k total. Um, it
was insane, dude. Unbelievable. Do do
you think that that triggered a bunch of
Argentinian hackers to like really dive
in
>> and like yeah I mean um just for you to
know like none of the above Leandro one
of the greatest hackers I know um I
invited him to the live hacking event
and he got his first bounty there.
>> Wow.
>> Um
>> delic uh he's also you know doing great
um pentesting back money hunting. He
also got one of first bugs or the first
bug. Um but yeah, there were a lot of
people from from Argentina that saw this
as okay, this actually, you know, it's
real, you know, uh it works. So they
started uh hacking from from there and
and after organizing that event or
helping actually because of course I
didn't do everything. Um I got hired for
hacker one. So that's where the BP of
marketing at the time was like, "Dude, I
love this. You know, I want you to work
with me." And I'm like,
>> "Sure, you
mean I'm definitely on board, but I I
kind of didn't trust him at the same,
you know, at the same time. I was like,
yeah, it's too good to be real, you
know?"
>> Um, and you put yourself out there, man.
I mean, you youororked your way into it,
right, at that event. And that is
definitely something that a lot of
hackers underestimate the power of.
>> Just ask, right? This is Douglas Daddy's
phrase, just ask. I mean, you literally
went up to Alex Rice and were like,
"Hey, let's do this in my country and
then it happened and then it changed the
lives of tons of local hackers." I mean,
that's an insane story.
>> And, you know, maybe maybe it's a little
bit of uh, you know, of luck, of fortune
there, right? Like, you know, he says,
"Okay, yeah, sure." You know, we'll do
it in and bonuses or whatever. And then,
you know, he's in a meeting a couple
months later and, you know, oh, this
comes up as a potential venue. And he's
like,
>> actually, I think I've got someone who
can help us with that. Like, and that
just kind of tips it over the the the
edge a little bit, right? Yeah.
>> Um, so if you're getting out there,
you're talking, you're you're putting
your dreams out there, um, it definitely
helps that that manifest, I think. Um,
guys, I'm not I'm not going to lie, man.
It's it's pretty sweet getting to sit
down and hear y'all's story because we
we've seen each other a lot, but I
haven't heard these backtories. Um, so
thanks for thanks for talking about that
um this time. And and and I did want to
ask you guys because um obviously, you
know, Reszo and I are uh living the
full-time Buck Bounty life, really
leaning into Buck Bounty. Um, and we
talk often about like
the fact that Bug Bounty is like our
dream, you know, and and I wanted to ask
you what brought you into the community
management side. Um, ver, you know, and
you guys are a very unique breed because
very few people ha have tasted the the
pen tester, the that book bounty hunter
lifestyle and then choose to do, you
know, a a different a different side.
Um, and I think a lot of that comes
from, you know, the love that you give
to the community and that sort of thing.
But I'm wondering what your why why you
made that decision to move into into
community um in the the bug bounty world
rather than um you know staying on on
the technical route and doing that from
your day-to-day
>> oh you go ahead you I'll let you point
to one in a minute. It feels a little
bit like Skeleton and Codingo or sorry
Skeleton and Hackloop because they kind
of were big hackers but then decided to
like support the community obviously in
a slightly different way but kind of
interesting. Yeah, you can you can
direct the question.
>> I'll give that to Harley first.
Well, the fact that you, you know, are
like, "Hey, you guys are kind of like
skeleton and hack Luke is insane." But
thank you. I'll take that compliment.
Um, but no, I mean, honestly, it wasn't
necessarily purposeful for me. Like, it
just happened naturally. Like, it keeps
happening naturally. Like, every time I
>> try to pivot into, you know, doing
something different where it's like
focusing on more technical roles, I
always just end up doing things like
this. And I think it's just
>> my passion for helping others and
>> um and and really like kind of like
trying to lift other people up and
>> like I think that that just is kind of
what's creating a lot of this.
>> Um even when I was going through school,
I was creating community like I founded
the cyber security program or cyber
security club um and brought people in.
And
>> me too, dude. Come on, do some let's go.
Yeah, dude.
>> That's how we do.
>> Yeah. But it's just like I feel like you
know you guys have talked about Bug
Bounty being sometimes lonely and
whatever
>> it is
>> like I think that part of it is just
looking to try to find people that you
can experience life with like you know
experience and have a journey together
and share wins and share losses keep you
motivated whatever. Um and then it's
just in that path of like always looking
for other people that I can kind of like
share things with. I've also been
wanting to help them and in exchange
like they've been helping me and I don't
know like just I feel like my career has
always benefited when I bring other
people around that also are trying to
like help people and
>> it's just
>> I don't know it's not really
>> that makes sense man you've got you've
got something that that pulls you
towards community that pulls you towards
people um rather than you know
necessarily towards the technical piece
and I I feel that man I mean when I'm
around you I'm like I I like you know
every time I see you I come up and give
you a big hug So, um, that's that's
great, man. And and Ari, I'd like to
hear your side as well because you were
you were doing the consultant life for a
while. You know, you were traveling
around, you were hacking stuff. Um, and
then you you you know, you chose to jump
on this bug bounty role where you're
helping with the live hacking event. So,
what what made you make that transition?
>> Yeah. Uh so so for me it was like again
you know like as I was sharing like the
passion to you know be part of this like
to be part of this community like
wanting hack one to be here uh and
trying to replicate what I was seeing in
Vegas and you know with all the top
hackers and things like that and and
what keeps me here is also you know I I
always say it's kind of corny like
sounds cliche maybe but it's like we are
changing people's lives you know we are
providing opport opportunities for
different people that in especially like
some people around the world that maybe
are outside of the US, right? Like I am
from Argentina.
>> I was going to say you see that
specifically, right? I mean that that
$12,000 bounty was what probably the
salary of a lot of your friends for a
year.
>> Yeah, 100%. and like you know making
that Saturday for me it's like dude um
this is life-changing and and providing
that same opportunity to others not only
in Argentina but Latin America or like
India or like whatever you know like
different countries that
think about this like you're making
literally the same exact money than
someone from the US is making you know
like you get the critical you just make
a 20k bounty or something someone in
India can make the same bounty or like I
can do it if I invest the time or have
the knowledge
>> and the equipment required is so low
compared to other industries too, right?
I mean, like if they can get a computer
and some of them even start with a
phone, right? I don't know if any of the
Argentinian hackers have. I know so many
Indian hackers that have just started
hacking with their phone. It's insane.
Like sometimes they they literally watch
some YouTube videos, they they watch
streams or something, they they start
doing recon or understand something and
and they they get a bug and suddenly
it's like, okay, that that is
life-changing. And
>> Mhm. it it you know again as I was
saying it sounds cliche but you know
when you face people in live hacking
events or or different events around the
world and they come to you and thank you
for it it's life-changing dude it's it's
like I feel appreciated and I feel like
what I'm doing it's you know it's worth
it and literally I had people come over
to me and say dude I love you and like I
don't even know you dude like who are
you I I am this username right oh you're
this oh amazing and dude thanks to you I
bought a house and I bought a my parents
house and I bought a car and you know
when they tell you that it's like it
means something for them and maybe what
I did it was just like you know inviting
them to a program or at the time making
them a pentester or
>> providing a like an invite you know what
whatever and and that changed you know
their life so that that is what keeps me
going honestly I besides I'm a she
hacker right and I kind of do what you
know stop hack somebody but um
definitely that's kind of what keeps me
going is keeps me motivated and and you
know it's hard and sometimes it's when
you see all the hate on social media and
and you always get like 90 90% negative
stuff and 5% positive you know like you
don't see all the positive things. So
sometimes it's complicated to you know
stay motivated or positive and and try
to keep doing the same things but then
when that single person comes to you and
say something nice uh it makes it work.
So
>> yeah, I mean they're only so passionate
and negative because it is
life-changing, right? It's like the
difference between the getting paid and
not especially like you said for for
some for some hackers in certain
countries, it's like it it's actually
life-changing. And so even if they're in
the wrong, like they've got to fight for
it tooth and nail because if they do get
paid, you know, it could it could
literally buy, you know, their their
entire family food for the next six
months or whatever. So the yeah and like
the equipment like think about this like
just to put a close on it like maybe
you're hacking from your phone like you
were saying and maybe making that bounty
allows you to buy a a MacBook and that
is your working tool for the next 5
years or something you know like it it's
life changing sometimes we don't realize
that.
>> Cool. Well yeah I mean the main uh goal
for this episode was to hear about you
both both you guys but but also
especially to hear a lot more about Bug
Bounty Village. Why don't you tell us
like in like two sentences like kind of
the the uh origin story of Bug Bounty
Village and then you know maybe some
some highlights about things that you
all are excited about this year. Did
anything change relative to last year?
You know maybe who are some of your key
speakers. So yeah two sentence origin
story and then let's talk about this
year.
>> Cool. I'll I'll start. Um so yeah but
but Bunny Village kind of came to be a
thing that we didn't expect to happen.
We submitted our application and we
heard, you know, other people were
trying to get a bug bounty village for a
couple years and we just submitted ours
thinking, okay, we'll throw our names in
the pool and I guess they loved our
application and and they were like,
yeah, let's do it. And so we had three
months last year to to pull it together
and, you know, the response was really
really positive. Uh this year some
things are definitely different. Um but
not not a ton. I mean, it's going to be
similar to last year. We have a lot of
the same speakers. Uh people like Hadex
Intamac
uh Rhinerator, some dude named Rerator.
>> Yeah, we
>> I'm excited.
>> We've got a lot a lot of awesome
speakers coming in and doing stuff. Um
we've also got some new things that are
happening this year. But before I talk
too much about that, Ari, did you want
to talk anything more about the origins?
Yeah, I mean as I was saying, you know,
like I think it has always been like a
passion project for me as well. Like we
didn't have a back money village. It to
me sounded stupid, you know, like why
why are people going to red team village
to talk about back money? I mean, I know
it's related, but also it's like it's
because they don't have a space. It's
because they don't have the space, you
know, like I I want to learn more about
Bakoney. It's a career. It's like a it's
an industry. like why we don't have a
space in the biggest conference of
hacking you know and to me it was like
we needed we need to be there we need we
need a space it was obvious um but at
the same time as how was saying like I
didn't think we were going to get
accepted and and also it depends a lot
on you know if your employer allows it
if you have the time to invest if you
have the money or you can get the
sponsors to to run it because it's so
freaking expensive dude and we we were
not prepared 100%.
I I will be honest with you. I submitted
the application form on the last day
from a hotel room. We like and and by
the way, thanks Jessica my manager which
was like have you submitted it?
>> [__]
>> I think I think we could all say thanks
Jessica for about 1500 things. Thank you
Jessica.
>> Thank you Jessica. And and yeah and she
was like damn boom. And and I submitted
it and of course I put a lot of work in
submission. it wasn't like uh just like
you know AI generated or something. Um
and they I I guess they like it. Um and
yeah, we were, you know, super happy and
also like immediately after like
panicking a lot, uh because it's like,
okay, what the hell is Defcon and and
now we're organizing something there?
And it's like we don't know anything at
all. And we kind of still feel that way
sometimes, but um uh but yeah, I I have
to say that, you know, the first year
was was great. uh was definitely
overwhelming but also like uh we were
super grateful with the support and and
you know all the speakers including you
Justin uh that invested the time on the
talks but also all the people that you
know was there trying to to to be a part
of it you know because it's you can do a
village and you can also not have anyone
coming in or saying ah actually the red
team village is six times the size I'm
not going to this small space you know
like and
>> how was the space
>> and that that happened It's definitely
small, dude. We We probably need like 10
times the space.
>> Yeah. I told him I I after the con, um I
walked up to to the village leads and I
said I said, "If you give us 10x the
space next year, we'll fill it." Like
give it to us. I'm confident. And
>> this year we got I think what 30% more
space. So not very much.
>> Jeez. Come on. Come on.
>> The podcast has grown a lot. The
industry's grown a lot. It's going to be
a long line. I think
>> it is. last year and we were literally
blocking the the pathway like for a lot
of the whole Defcon like people were
lined up. Dude,
>> I literally know people who spent 3
hours waiting in line just to get inside
the village which
>> sounds crazy but when you really sit
down and think about how many hours the
like Defcon as a whole is open like it's
only like what eight hours a dayish,
right? 8 to 10 hours a day. So to spend
three hours
>> is insane. That's that's a decent
portion of your experience. I definitely
>> luckily there was a good amount of stuff
going on on in the line as well, you
know, like, you know, I I know that me
and and um some of the crew were kind of
walking up and down the line talking
about critical thinking stuff, giving
out swag, you know, that sort of thing.
So maybe we can do some some line
entertainment again because it's going
to need
>> we're going to need it, man. I think
it's really cool because like like a lot
of the bug bounty people that it's
typically before bug bounty village all
all of us would be pretty like
distributed right like we might be at
recon village we might be at red team
village
>> you know and and now I feel like we
actually have a home um and we can bring
a lot of people into like this central
place and exactly that like even though
there's a big line um you know there's a
lot of cool swag and different
challenges too we also have lined up and
we can talk about some of that this year
but you know in addition to people like
you coming in and and just kind of
hanging out in line or talking to
people. Um, we're going to also have
challenge coins that we can give people
to solve while they're waiting in line.
We're going to have a a CTF this year
where people can actually try to to
compete. Um, so definitely happy to talk
more about that for sure.
>> Yeah. What what's what's the deal with
the CTF? Who's who's making it? Um,
how's it how's it going to be run?
>> All right. So, I'm actually really
excited about this because I I didn't
really want a CTF. I I ultimately what I
wanted to see have this like do was
let's get some real like programs in and
let's do like actual almost like a mini
life hacking event type thing, right? Um
and the logistics of that knowing
firsthand from being on the hacker one
side would be a nightmare to actually
try to pull off for a number of reasons.
Maybe one day we'll figure it out in the
future. Um but in reality it wasn't
going to happen this year. And so we
were like, well, what else can we do to
where it's still going to be a hands-on
hacking activity? And um you see a lot
of CTFs where it's like, here's a
password hash, now crack it. Okay, you
get a flag. Like cool. Um but not what
we wanted. And so what really what we
envisioned was like an intentionally
vulnerable web application that you
don't have instructions, you're not
guided, you don't have a path. is just
like here's this environment,
>> go hack it, right? And maybe there's a
program page that talks about what's in
scope and what's allowed and whatever.
Um, and so we wanted it to feel like a
real bug bounty situation where you're
just going to this website and you find
a bug and you write a report and then
that report gets triaged and you get
points based on your report. And so that
was kind of like the vision. And so we
started reaching out to a bunch of
vendors to try to make this happen. And
man, we probably talked to what, like a
dozen different people in like a week
trying to trying to make this happen.
And then we finally came across uh these
guys uh based out of Dubai. They're
called CTF AE and they were just super
passionate about about the project. We
hopped on a call and they were super
excited about it. um they've done really
big CTFs for Black Hat in in that region
before and so they definitely have the
experience that they you know to do
something at the scale we need.
>> Um so yeah they they've kind of like
taken the idea and they've expanded on
it and ran with it. And so now we have
this web application but it's not just
one. It's like multiple applications
that have
>> APIs and there's LLM components and it's
like this holistic system.
>> Yeah.
So all
>> yeah I want I want wanted to add that
you know it's definitely kudos to them
for being so passionate about it as well
like and and trying to take it to the
next step. We haven't seen some things
and it looks great. Uh and again it's
like has an NLM and and like different
type of box. It's not going to be the
typical, oh, it's a cross scripting and
and you get a flag, you know, it's going
to be a lot of things and and we're also
going to be having volunteers that are
some of those are triashers from
different platforms and they will be
triaging your books. So, it's definitely
we kind of scale it if we do like a real
triage scenario where, you know, we'll
have thousands of submissions and they
will triage the whole thing, but at
least we'll, you know, review the report
and we'll see, are you making a
oneliner, dude? You're not going to get
points for that. You know, like you need
to write a proper back money report to
actually you know get some extra points.
So eventually what what we expect is
that the new people coming to Vakani
will have a a learning experience of the
whole thing right like you read the
policy
read the policy understand the scope you
actually hack the scope you find the bug
you submit a report and someone triashes
it and you get a communication there. So
that is to me it's great because it's
you know again like for the new people
will be super super uh educational right
they they will learn the whole process
and and they will also hack have fun
heck
>> and then for yeah then for the experts
like you guys like you will have a nice
challenge because you know the the the
challenges will be some will be easy of
course no hanging fruit but some will be
like you know the one of those you want
to quit and and you know break
everything and and and you will be
stressed so uh we expect to have you a
challenge for for all the all the
experience levels. So
>> that's awesome, man. Yeah, I I love the
idea of having a CTF that is that like
represents the bug bounty process,
right? The a lot of the the ambiguity of
bug bounty, right? Where you're like,
uh, you know, the thing about CTFs is,
oh, there's always a solution, but
you're you're emulating that a little
bit here by giving them a full app with
minimal instructions, right? And and you
know, they may be going down this path
and it's actually, you know, there's not
a bug there, you know? Um but but this
this seems like an accurate
representation with the reports with the
where do I go, what do I do, you know,
sort of uh having to overcome that
paralysis to solve these these ETFs.
>> Yeah, 100%. And and just just to add to
that like these guys are building it,
they first created the whole web app
without the vulnerabilities and and then
they are adding specific
vulnerabilities. So it's not like you
know everything's broken and you will
just you know everything is destroyed by
by the star. It's like they actually
create a whole app working functionally
and then they are adding the bug. So
this you know also will feel like um
harder you know it's again like you
don't know where to look you will have
to test all the features all the
functionalities do all the you know like
like you do in background you create an
account you you buy something you know
you you do something to actually have
more scope you know see more API
endpoints
>> dude heck yeah let's go this is what I'm
talking about
>> I have I have a question are you all
going to deliver dupes
>> that that's something I wanted to do
actually uh I proposed that. I I was
thinking in you know like what if we
create a dupe so they also get
frustrated from that and you know like
we actually get the real experience um I
think it might be a challenge for us to
do that.
>> Uh but we're thinking that maybe you
know uh we'll have specific challenges
for inerson people at Defcon uh because
we cannot triage thousands of reports
right in in real time. So, we'll gate it
to in person people at Defcon and maybe,
you know, we can come with something up
and and see if we can dupe some bugs.
Maybe the first three flags are valid
and then the other ones
>> are you could have a lower threshold for
the dupe like since you have a count on
the number of flags. Maybe it's like if
you're the if you're more like if you're
the top 10, it's not a dupe, but if it's
greater than 10, you get a big warning
that's like duplicate, you know, you
were the 11th
>> or you get a little bit less points
because you you you were later to the
party, you know, like really like in
back. So, yeah. where be super cool. Or
or what you could do is just everybody's
first bug is a dupe no matter what it
is. It's like everyone's got a dupe the
first one and then it starts like a
two-hour timer and it's like okay
reopened uh triage, you know, like that
sort of thing to give them that little
like, you know, sort of feeling. I I
love it, dude. Frick. That's awesome.
>> And just to be clear, the the CTF will
be open to the internet. It will be
something that anybody, even if you're
not going to Defcon, you can still
participate. Um, we're just going to
gate the triage experience to be
in-person attendees only just because we
can't scale triage.
>> Yeah. Oh, absolutely. That makes sense.
Um, guys, we'll we'll put it up on the
screen now. Uh, Richard, if you could
put up the the view of the DevCon layout
that they have there. Um, looks like we
have a little bit more space this year.
What What kind of stuff do you guys have
in mind for the space? Uh, that's that's
difference from last year. Yes, we we
made some key changes to you know you'll
notice like there's a podium with the
TVs on either side. We had that same
type of setup last year inside the
village. Um, but last year we kind of
set it up more classroom style where you
had tables and you could sit down with a
laptop because of just how crazy the
line was and how many people got
frustrated for not being able to come in
and you know people were literally
sitting on the floor like
>> we just decided look like ideally we
would have space for tables so people
can bring laptops
>> but we are going to value you know just
letting more people in
>> their laptops decision Yeah, exactly.
Yeah. S smart decision.
>> Yeah.
>> So, so we removed the table so we could
fit more seats.
>> So, it's 30% more like floor space, but
then also taking the tables out probably
gave back another 30 or 40% I would say.
Right.
>> 100%. Yeah. Like I think last year we
had I want to say 30 to 40 chairs
whereas this year I think that number is
like 70. And so um at least for right in
front of the podium and so that that'll
be helpful. And then we also kind of are
dividing the room in half. So we're
going to have these dividers where, you
know, you'll have the speaker doing
whatever it is that they're doing. And
then in the back half of the room is
going to be more of like a quiet area
where there's couches and ottomans that
people can come in and sit on. And the
idea there is we'll have the leaderboard
for the CTF up on a TV back there. And
so if they want to come in and sit down
and hack inside the village and chat
with friends, meet people, network and
collab with, they can. um and and
hopefully not disrupt the speaker too
much.
>> Yeah, I I think that's a great idea. And
I I think also just speaking back to the
CTF versus real bug bounty thing, the
way that these live hacking events
started in the first place was people at
Defcon were just like, "Hey, I'm going
to go hack on this target. You want to
do it with me?" You know, so like I
think there's this this component of um
the the whole beauty of Bug Bounty is
its accessibility in a lot of ways,
right? And so at the end of the day, if
you guys have a space where people are
just going to sit and hack, um, and we
say, you know, here are the top, you
know, 50 programs or whatever from each,
you know, each platform or whatever.
Pick pick pick them and and go after
these public targets, right, together,
then that could also be a really cool
environment.
>> Yeah, I think I think the the future
definitely looks like like that. We
definitely want to do something in that
regard in the future. But it's also a
huge challenge when when the back the
the backing village at Defcon is
platform agnostic, right? So
>> um in order to avoid having like
preference or avoid having like a single
platform there or like a sponsored
platform that pays you know like
>> um you will need to make them all
welcome and everyone should have uh like
space and and organizing that with all
the platforms that want to participate.
It's like chaos and also like if triage,
you know, doesn't triage on time, like
you need suddenly five different triage
from different platforms and it's like I
don't know how to scale it. I think it's
a future. We're just not there yet. Um
but definitely it's interesting.
>> I mean I mean absolutely and I and I
think I mean without the platform's
permission you can grab the top five
five from Hacker One, top five from from
Bug Crowd, top five from Yes, We Hack,
top five from Integrity or whatever,
right? throw them up on a board, say,
"Hey, these are the top five programs,
you know, by by payouts, and you know,
sure, they're not going to get paid out
on the spot, so it's not going to feel
like an LH quite as much, which which
does affect the experience, but at the
end of the day, if you're sitting there
collabing and your buddy's like, "Oh, I
popped something." Like, heck, I'm
walking out of DevCon with cash
positive. What's the heck up with that?
Um, then I think that would be really,
really sick.
>> 100%. And I mean, you know, I kind of
feel like we are we're creating that
environment already, right, where it's
like,
>> yeah, we're not broadcasting specific
programs necessarily, but people 100%
are making connections going to their
hotel room and and popping bounties.
Like, I've I've talked to many people
who who did that exact thing last year.
So,
>> for sure.
>> Um, I am looking at this doc and I am
seeing a very cool badge. Uh, what
what's going on with this? How do we get
our hands on these bad boys? Oh man. All
right. So, these badges, we had badges
last year. Um the these are like last
year's except nothing like last year's
and way better.
Um and anyway, we partnered with a guy
named Abanov Hackerware. Uh he does a
lot of great work for a lot of villages
and hacker cons. He was kind of like the
genius that made this badge come to
life. And it's got like this cool like
blinky matrixy type effect in the
background where it like rains binary
code. You can't see that here really on
on the still image. Um but we've got
videos that we can share. And anyway,
I'm just super thrilled for this badge.
You'll notice there are a few buttons at
the bottom if you have a keen eye. And
we didn't have this last year. And so
these buttons will do things. And I
don't know how how much we want to
describe here. Uh, but we do plan on
integrating various challenges into our
badge. And so, um, you'll see challenge
coins from various platforms that may or
may not resolve to a binary flag that
punch into this badge and make the badge
do different things. So, it'll be really
cool. Um, I'll leave it at that. Ari, do
you want to talk about it?
>> Yeah, I I feel like since this pro is
going to be airing at, you know, end of
July, like we can share a little bit
more. Uh there will be like dates from
Defcon. Uh but yeah like the challenge
thing uh the challenge coin thing is
something like at least with hackon we
have been doing it for the last three
years. I have been creating these easy
you know approachable challenges that
are fun. Um for someone that never
solved like a crypto challenge before
and by crypto mean we mean cryptography
not you know cryptocurrencies. And it's
kind of fun. And you normally have like
two sides of the coin. So you have like
some hints and and you can you know do
some some cool stuff. Last year we did
it for Bagon Village and and this year
we you know we put that into
sponsorship. So um Hagrin is actually
sponsoring the coins again and we'll
have this challenge that if you solve
you know you can get these you know
buying everything and then you'll type
it in in the in the badge. So, ideally,
you'll, you know, you'll have some
lights. You'll have a couple of
challenges and and if you unlock
everything, we'll be able to tell that
you unlock everything. We'll see. Maybe
we have some giveaways or some cool.
>> How many badges are there?
>> Yeah. So, we have 400 of these blue ones
that we're giving away. Okay.
>> Um, and that's shout out to Inspective
for that. They were the sponsor who made
that happen. And so, thank you,
Inspective, for for making this
possible.
>> How do we get them?
>> Yeah. So to get them, they're going to
be given away at random. Um you kind of
have to earn them right place, right
time. Also, if you're doing great things
for the village, we'll recognize that.
Um so if you come in and you're helping
people or you know, you're volunteering
or whatever the case is, we'll
definitely hook you up with a badge.
Otherwise, you know, stay stay in the
loop on our socials to be on the lookout
for agenda. Last year, we were giving
people who were like the first people in
the village every day. we were giving
them badges for like the first, you
know, 40 people that showed up or
something like that. Um, so yeah,
there'll be lots of opportunities to get
your hands on one. I would say maybe
follow, you know, all of the socials and
and look for announcements.
>> Heck yeah, dude. I'm going to be I'm
going to be looking for that.
>> I also have another another announcement
to the badges to to share. So
>> Oh, really?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. All right. Well Well, hold on. We
got a we got another announcement about
the badges. Hit me. What's the
announcement with the badges? So, I
mentioned we'll have 400 of these blue
ones, right?
>> Oh,
>> but we're going to have another variant.
And the other variant is actually one
that if you want to make sure you get a
badge, you can purchase one. Um, and so
we've got a we've got a green variant
that is limited. We're only making 200
of those. Um, and those are actually
available for pre-orders right now if
you're watching this at the end of July.
>> Nice.
>> Um, and so if you go to
shop.bugdefcon.com, bugdown.com.
You'll be able to purchase yourself a
green badge and you'll want to only
we're not shipping them, so you'll need
to purchase it and then pick it up
inside the village during Defcon. Um but
yeah, we do expect these to sell out.
>> Oh, heck yeah. Heck yeah, they will. I
love it. Green the green ones for the
green hat, right? That's
>> it's um it's a custom edition. Yeah, we
we try to make it a little bit
different, more exclusive. And also, you
know, just for for everyone listening to
know, it's like you're literally helping
the village to be run by purchasing a
batch. Uh we are going to take those,
you know, those batches money to pay a
lot of other things that are like uh
costing us a lot of money to run. So,
you know, keep that in mind. If you like
the badge, definitely get one. If you
like to help us, definitely get one as
well. Um but yeah, just remember you
need to pick those up in
>> that would be a cool booth for future
years like um basically like contribute
to the like basically what's it called
like fund like fund the bug bounty
village. So like when you're sitting at
that table if you find a bug sitting
there like that money goes to the bug
bounty village. That would be really
cool to do.
>> Yeah. Guys give us give us a handle you
know that we can add in in as a
collaborator on some of our reports and
donate some some money to the to the bug
bounty village. That
>> that would be really cool.
infinite login.
>> Richard, just Richard, just beep that
and change it to reszo if you don't
mind.
>> Yeah. My gosh.
Um, all right guys. Well, thank you so
much for all your hard work on the
bugani village. Super appreciate that.
Um, uh, we'll we'll pivot a little bit
now to, uh, Harley's stuff. He's got a
ton of stuff going on. Um uh so Harley,
you this is what I was saying before.
Like dude, you you are producing so much
crap right now. Like I can't I don't
understand how you do all this stuff at
once. Like I'm like and and it's all
high qual like the disclosed news
newsletter. Dude, we've been working on
the critical thinking newsletter for a
long time. And when I saw the quality of
that newsletter, I was like, dang, he's
doing some work. Um and then now you're
telling me you got an ebook and you're
working on Bug Bounty Village. So, how
the freak are you doing this?
>> Honestly, dude, I've just been kind of
obsessing lately. I think I'm getting
really inspired by like the capabilities
of AI and like what we're able to do
now. I'm able to be way more productive
than I ever have been before. Um, the
newsletter thing to be honest with you,
like I think in the past, like two years
ago, I would have never been able to do
it. But because AI is where it's at,
I've been able to build automation that,
you know, it does a lot of the work for
me. Like I'm literally scraping, you
know, Twitter and YouTube and all these
different things. If someone links to a
blog, I'm scraping that. I'm summarizing
things and I'm having it automatically
rank like high quality content. And so,
and then I vibe coded this like front
end that's like lets me easily see the
feed of all the different book the book.
>> I saw that in the doc, man. Richard, put
put the um behind the scenes one up on
the up on the screen right now. He's got
like content feed V2 with like this
beautiful screenshot. I love what Vibe
coding does for us, man. Like that we
can so easily build these little like
backends and stuff that make our our
day-to-day data processing so much
easier.
>> Yeah. And literally like I only showed
the feed screen, but like this is like a
whole like newsletter editorial app
where you can approve content, reject
it, move it to the prep section where
you reorganize and you know, edit and
then you click generate and it writes it
in your voice using AI. Like it just,
you know, it also allows for the human
in the loop component, which I do think
is very valuable. Like instead of
spending, you know, 20 hours a week
doing this all manually, I'm spending
like 2 hours on the weekend and I'm
still spending time and I'm still doing,
you know, the human in the loop
component to actually make sure the
content is high quality. Um, but it's
it's enabled me to do that where I
couldn't have before.
>> Yeah. When I saw one of your posts
recently, I think that I was like, "Oh,
I wonder what Sassy's using on the back
end. like what alternative to beehive or
whatever else is he using? That's crazy.
It was just vibe coded.
>> That's sick, dude. That's absolutely
sick. And then on top of that, we have
disclosed online, which we've mentioned
on the pod before. Uh you know, sort of
aggregating hacker profiles across all
the bug bounty platforms. Um tell tell
me a little bit about your about your
vision for that and what your what your
hopes are for for where that'll go.
>> So for that, honestly, what I just was
born on a weekend. I think it was like
Memorial Day weekend or something and I
had an extra day and I was like, "What
do I want to build?" Um, and I had this
idea of like building the hacker
directory and so I I did that and I
don't know like what really happened is
I spent like 24 hours kind of building a
lot of it just for myself for fun and
then uh I saw somebody post online. It
was actually the Thanks for sharing the
screen. Yeah, this is this is it. Um the
other one the hackedin.net is what it
ended up becoming. Uh but before he
released that, he posted about it and
that tweet was like getting a lot of
traction. And so I was like, "Oh, like
actually I've been already doing this."
So that kind of like inspired me to just
grind it out for the next couple days to
actually push it and make it live. Um
and so yeah, that's what this is. And
dude, it's just really cool to see like
what you can
>> It's pretty, man. It's It's a pretty
website. I dig it. Um and and you know,
we we talked we covered it on the pod
before. Um I is this going to be
something that you're going to continue
to work on you think or uh is this sort
of like a vibe coded project um that
that like like for example verifications
takes a lot of work on the back end
right if you're going to send
verification emails or something like
that is that something you plan on
integrating or
>> honestly it was a side thing that I just
kind of whipped up and people thought it
was cool I used it as like a lead gen
for my newsletter because I was also
releasing the newsletter around the same
time. Oh, hey, speaking of the
newsletter, I know that we mentioned it
a minute ago, but I have been getting so
many subscribers to my to my email list
for my blog post via yours. So, thanks
for that,
>> dude. Yeah, of course. Again, happy to
build up people, right? And and you're
building me up by giving me this
platform. Like, happy to happy to return
the favor. And um but yeah, like the the
newsletter, you can, by the way, you can
find it at gitdisclosed.com.
Uh would love if you would take a moment
to to subscribe. But that was really the
intention once I built this. I was like,
"Okay, it could be a cool lead funnel
for that. This, it's not a startup. It's
not a platform that I'm, you know, going
to make money on or really investing any
more time in other than what it's at
today." Um, do I think that there's a
million things we could do? For sure. I
could even expand this to where, you
know, we start advertising programs and,
you know, people start leaving reviews
about programs or even reviews about
hackers. Maybe that might be dangerous.
But there's a lot you can
>> there's a lot we could do.
>> We could finally organize the union.
>> Done.
>> Oh my gosh, dude.
>> But no, I mean, my my focus my focus is
is on my full-time job. Uh my focus is
on Bug Bounty Village and then and then
the disclose newsletter with with any of
my extra time.
>> Nice, man. Well, it is an amazing
product. Uh I I really appreciate the
way that you've used AI to optimize your
workflow and still deliver a really high
quality result. Um, and I I'll say like
newsletters are there are some people
that are really into newsletters. I
don't really consume newsletters that
much besides this one. Uh, and and uh
one of the ways that I consume it is is
through your exposts um that you do
where you kind of take a an X version of
that newsletter and and put it into the
into X. And I think that's a really
really awesome um thing you're doing
there. So definitely would love to see
you continue doing that.
It's good to know. Thank you.
>> Yeah. Um All right. Oh, dude. So, but so
we going back to the disclos thing
though. It got hacked a little bit
though, right? Can you can you talk a
little bit about that story because I
thought that was hilarious.
>> Okay. Yeah. So, I I actually tried to
make things better and that's how I got
hacked. So, let me let me let me run
through it. So, um you know, I vibe
coded the front end. The way that I I
always vibe code apps is is I build the
automation separate. And so you know the
automation and all that like is actually
run through um inn which is like a low
code automation platform like make or
zap year. And so I do a lot of the
automation through that populate a
superbase database and then build the
front end using like lovable or you know
whatever other vibe coding tool you like
to use. And when I was building this out
a lot of the vulnerabilities that I
introduced actually were because of
superbase configurations. And so what I
found after I built this, I originally
was going to let people self-register to
create an account on the directory. I
later decided to remove that and turn it
into like a lead funnel where you have
to subscribe um to the newsletter to get
an account. But when I first created
that, I didn't remove like I removed the
front end of Superbase authentication,
but I didn't actually remove it from
like the Superbase config. And so people
could hit the API directly and still
self-register an account and basically,
you know, force them into the into the
database. And so that was one bug that's
less critical. Um, but that was one bug
that got that got sorted out. The other
bug that was way more critical was I
noticed because I just kind of was like
poking at my own app a little bit that
in the response you would leak all of
the information about you know the the t
like if you query a record in the table
you would see everything about that user
which is intentional it's all public
data but there was one field that I
didn't want to be exposed which was
email because when you would
self-register and originally you would
provide an email so I was like, okay,
how do I fix this? And so I'm
researching how to fix this in Postgress
and I came across views in Postgress.
And so I was like, all right, I'm going
to make a view that basically queries
all the same stuff. It just excludes the
email field. What I didn't know is that
when you create a view in Postgress, it
doesn't respect uh RLS policies like
tables do. And so it it actually is
configured with the permissions of the
user who creates it, which is really
stupid.
>> But that means when I created this view,
I essentially gave everybody
unauthenticated admin access because my
view was created as an admin user.
>> Oh no.
>> Brutal.
>> Oh jeez.
>> Yeah. So, I had a researcher uh who, you
know, decided to to kind of pone me and
go through all my records in my database
and change all of the profile images for
everybody to his avatar
>> and then change the bios of everybody
and you know, it's like like yeah, I
think you took it too far. You could
have could have done better, but I was
just happy that he worked with me to
help me figure out what the what that
was.
>> Were you able to undo it?
>> Yeah, it was pretty easy. was like,
well, once I thought it was an RLS
problem and so like I'm spending a ton
of time lowle security I'm spending a
ton of time like trying to solve like
like okay why is this not working? I
thought I had that restricted and it
wasn't until later I figured out the
view thing. Um but he actually inspired
me to build viode another tool. It's a
it's a you know like a superbase
security scanner that will you know grab
all of the different tables out of the
swagger that's exposed in superbase and
then query all those and test write
records and all this stuff. Um and so I
was able to kind of build that out and
honestly I think there's a product
opportunity to
>> where is it Harley? Where is where's the
tool?
>> Uh it's private man.
>> Give me the tool Harley. We were just
talking about that on the pod. We just
like what was it a couple weeks ago we
mentioned uh shell found a you know some
weird quirk with suva base right where
you get less than greater than uh uyu
IDs and then we were like oh we should
create a scanner and then
>> damn it
>> yeah I've already got the scanner um I
actually saw that and and I'm going to
implement that into the scanner so
>> well then you have to share it right
then then it all of a sudden enters
public domain and it's open source and
you have to share it with us so
>> gosh dude
>> yeah sure I'll share it for $9.99 a
month
>> oh jeez here we go he's he's got the
he's got the bug. He's got the Legion uh
bug. No, that's great though, man. And
and you know, big big fan of obviously
sharing with the community, but also big
fan of keeping the stuff that you that
you want to keep private private. That's
the name of the game with Bug Bounty. Um
so,
>> but yeah, it was cool because it it
allowed for this cool story and so like
I posted about it on Twitter and like it
went crazy and you know, I definitely
used a clickbaity title of like I voded
this and got hacked and a lot of people
were just like retweeting it without
reading it and making fun of it. that I
actually tried to provide value in the
thread. And
>> anyway, I thought I thought it was a
pretty cool story. And I do think
there's an opportunity like so many
people are vi coding and shipping apps
right now that they don't know what
they're doing.
>> Um I think if someone were to step in
and try to release a product that's
specifically for like securing vibe
coded apps, I think that they could
really
>> Can someone explain why this is not a
feature for GitHub? Like why why do we
not have like automated GitHub code
review? I just don't understand. Yeah,
>> it's obviously not going to test the
whole app. Like it probably wouldn't
have worked for your view, right? I
don't know if a view is like um a state
via code. If it's not, then it wouldn't
have worked in that case, right? Because
it's like a platform as a service
vulnerability or a SAS. Like, you know,
it's like in the it's actually in the
DB, not in the code itself. But yeah, we
definitely need that.
>> Yeah, that's exactly right. Like, and I
think that that's the play, right? Is if
someone built a tool that's specific to
like querying the database um and
securing that because I do think you're
right. like there's probably solutions
out there that can secure the code. Um,
but it's like the misconfigurations in
the database that I think are really
leaking a lot of stuff.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Absolutely, man. Yeah. I'm
glad you jumped on that opportunity
though with Superbase because a lot of
people are are are using that and
setting that up. Um, so it's good to see
some some technology going out around
it. That's very reactive. Um, all right
guys, I think that's all we had in the
doc. Make sure you check out lots of
things. All right, listen listen closely
here guys. We got getdiscloed.com.
Subscribe to the newsletter. Great
newsletter. Love it. We've got
bugbountydefcon.com.
Right. That's where you get your badges.
That's where you learn about bug bounty
defcon where we're all going to be come
this August. We got disclosed online if
you want to get that a aggregating
hacking uh profile. And if you want to
see some of Harley's aka infinite login
past YouTube videos, you can find that
on his YouTube channel. It's just
infinite login, right Harley?
>> Yep. Exactly right.
>> Awesome. Well, Harley Ari, thank you
guys so much for coming on the pod
today. We will see you at uh at Defcon
at Bug Bunny Village.
>> Thank you so much for having us.
>> Thanks, guys.
>> Thank you so much.
>> Peace.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh or if
you want to support the show, head over
to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. Trust me. All right, I'll
see you there.